RESUME

RAJESH TIWARI

CURRENT ADDRESS: Jaypee Kosmos 36 Sector 134 Noida.

MOBILE: +91 8737869633; +91 7827769766

EMAIL: rajesh196.tiwari@gmail.com



Microsoft Certified Professional ID: 11397789

Career Objective

Total 4.5 years of experience in IT Technical Support that includes Troubleshooting end user's issues, Desktop support, Remote support, Application installation/repair, OS related troubleshooting and Application management. A proactive and optimistic personality with ability to provide first & second level of technical support on Call/Remote/Emails to Enterprise Users related to Office 365 end user's issue, Outlook client, MS Teams, Exchange online OS related issues, user and password management through Active Directory and other service-related tasks.

Employment Details

Global IT Support Analyst Rieke Packaging

Oct 2021- till date

Roles

- Provided day to-day onsite technical support for customers in a variety of work environments to include test, operational, and support networks.
- Exchange O365 account administration\ troubleshooting
- Exchange calendar/shared folder permissions and delegation
- Perform/create queries and user account in office 365
- Office O365/ Exchange online Administration- User Management
- Cloud\AD\ Exchange Server Enterprise account administration (modifies and manages user accounts and group permissions and assign licenses to user)
- Reset User Passwords and Account Creation using Windows Active Directory Domain Services Active Directory Users profile related issues.
- Troubleshooting and Applying Group Policies on client side and generating reports.
- Troubleshooting IP assignation, DHCP, DNS, VPN & Name Resolution related issues.
- Application management (Installation, uninstallation, Repair), OS related troubleshooting and installation.
- Administering user accounts, permissions, backups, troubleshoot network problems on Windows servers.
- Installed and configured local area network and replaced cabling and hardware and Documented network connections and LAN setups.
- Windows updates and fixes and security patch management and deployment.
- Support Active Directory, Terminal Server, etc.
- Handling calls and tickets through SNOW portal and handling calls as on on-call support.
- Installing Windows and OS updates on VM's physical nodes configured through WSUS.
- Replaced hardware as needed, installed operating systems and loaded new software configurations. Installed
 printers, plotters, laptops, thin clients, and stand-alone workstations. Repaired printers, copiers,
 workstations, and servers.
- Troubleshoot network connectivity issues. Resolved numerous troubles call tickets in a timely manner and documented resolution.
- Installed thin clients and helped users with their virtual desktops.
- I also provided help with resolving technical issues with accounts, passwords, logins, software, and other technical issues. Provided remote assistance for users worldwide.

System Engineer Dec 2019 - 2021

Team Computers, Iris Technologies (Client Side)

Roles

- Provide Desktop Support to the Clients from Financial Domain i.e., CitiGroup.
- Windows troubleshooting: Windows Server Support & Windows Desktop Support.
- Reset User Passwords and Account Creation using Windows Active Directory Domain Services Active Directory Users profile related issues.
- Troubleshooting and Applying Group Policies on client side and generating reports.
- Troubleshooting IP assignation, DHCP, DNS, VPN & Name Resolution related issues.
- Application management (Installation, uninstallation, Repair), OS related troubleshooting and installation.
- Handling calls and tickets through SNOW portal and handling calls as on on-call support.
- Installing Windows and OS updates on VM's physical nodes configured through WSUS.
- Troubleshooting client-side DNS & Name resolution related issues.
- Managing File Shares Disk and Drives for Central Access & Troubleshooting file folder permission related issues.

Engineer Desk-side May 2019 – Dec 2019

Progressive, AON Consulting (Client Side)

Roles

Installing, Upgrading, and Migrating to Windows 7/8

- Configuring Disks, Device Drivers, File Access, Printers, Network Connectivity, Wireless Network Connections & Applications
- Optimizing and Maintaining Windows 7 Client Computers
- Configuring Remote Access in Windows 7/8
- Performing backup recovery and System restore.

Support Associate July 2018 – April 2019

Cogent E-Services

Roles

- Supporting customers/clients in troubleshooting technical issues related to hardware devices, software components.
- Addressing user tickets regarding hardware, software and Networking.
- Extend computer support for system's software and hardware, setup computers and install software for various applications and programs.
- Hands-on experience with Windows/Linux environments.
- Record technical issues and solutions in logs.
- Application support like MS Office, Outlook 2013, CRM, McAfee, Skype for Business, TeamViewer.
- Install and test desktop software applications and internet browsers.
- Troubleshooting technical problems within organization like installation, configuration and troubleshooting operating system components, antivirus installation, smart end point & worked on tickets.

Technical Skills

Operating Systems

Windows 7, 10,11, Windows server 2012, 2016, 2019.

Windows Server Applications & Services

- Installing, Configuring and Managing Windows Active Directory Domain Services, Active Directory Sites & Services, Active Directory Domain and Trusts, Troubleshooting ADDS Kerberos Authentication & Logon Issues, Checking Active Directory Replication Issues through DcDiag, Event Viewer and services.
- Managing AD Users, Groups, OU's, Containers, Domain Controllers, AD Users Profiles, Logon Scripts, AD Users and Group Policies, Bulk Changes on Users, Groups, OUs via AD PowerShell & Active Directory Administrative center, Pulling AD related Reports, generating last login reports etc.
- Installing, Configuring and Managing Group Policy Configurations through Group Policy Management Console. Generating RSOP, Security Group filtering, WMI filtering, Group Policy Preferences, Group Policy Processing order, troubleshooting client-side related GPO issues, Generating Applied Group Policy results.
- Installing, Configuring and Managing DNS & DHCP, Managing DNS records, Managing DNS Replication, Backup and Restore, Managing DNS Zones Forward Lookup, Reverse Lookup, Stub Zones, Active Directory integrated Zones, Managing DHCP Scopes, Reservations, MAC Filtering, High Availability of DNS and DHCP.
- Managing windows firewalls through GPO, Deploying Antivirus software through GPO, managing printers, managing file and folder share permissions, VMware Workstation.
- Troubleshooting VPN, MS Outlook, MS Teams, Device Drivers, Backup and Recovery, Related issues.
- Installing, Configuring and Managing Windows Server (2012, 2106, 2019) Operating Systems, Installing Server Core & Nano Server.
- Installing, Configuring and Managing Windows Deployment Servers Configuring Boot Images, deployment Images & Custom Images, Joining new deployed Machines to Active Directory.
- Installing, Configuring and Managing WSUS servers and configuring clients to get updates from WSUS.
- Installing, Configuring and Managing Hyper-V Virtual Machines Implementing Microsoft Virtualization through Hyper-V, Configuring and Managing Local Storage, Virtual Hard Disk, VHD, Resizing Volumes, RAID, Quota management.
- Installing configuring and managing, FSRM, DFS, File server, Managing Data through Data de-duplication file classification and archiving and expiration policies.
- Installing, Configuring and Managing High Availability and Load balancing through windows Failover clustering and network load balancing, Configuring SAN through ISCSI Target and ISCSI Initiator, validating Failover clusters. Performing Health check.

Basic Knowledge of Languages

Basic Knowledge of programming, C, C++, HTML, Windows PowerShell.

Technical Qualification

MCSA : Microsoft Certified Solution Associate

Upgrading your skills to MCSA windows 8 (Exam code 70-689)

MCITP : Microsoft Certified IT Professional

Upgrading your skills to MCSA windows 8 (Exam code 70-685)

: Microsoft Certified Technical Specialist **MCTS**

TS: Windows 7 Configuring (Exam code 70-680)

MCP : Microsoft Certified Professional

: Hardware card level engineering course from IIHT Delhi CompTIA A+ Course

CompTIA N+ Course : Networking course from IIHT Delhi.

MCSA Windows Server 2012 Course : Completed MCSA course that includes 70-410, 70-411, 70-412

from a trainer and did self-study on topics like AD, DNS, DHCP, Hyper-V, File Services, GPO's and other Server Roles & Features.

Educational Qualification

Pursing Last Year from, Swami Vivekananda Subharti University MCA

BCA 2018 From, (MCRPV) 12th UP Board 2015 (PCM)

10th CBSE board 2012

Personal Details

Father Name Lt. Ravi Shankar Tiwari

Marital StatusSingleNationalityIndian

Language Known Hindi, English

Strengths Sincere, Fast Learner, Team Player

Hobbies and interest playing cricket, reading books, watching you tube videos

Declaration-

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned information is correct up to my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the above-mentioned particulars.

(RAJESH TIWARI)
